<?xml version="1.0"?>
<register_map name="ADF5355" num_bits="32">
    <register address="0x00" default_value="0x2006B0" name="REG0">
        <field name="INT" bits="19:4">
        The 16 INT bits (Bits[DB19:DB4]) set the INT value, which
        determines the integer part of the feedback division factor. The
        INT value is used in Equation 3 (see the INT, FRAC, MOD, and
        R Counter Relationship section). All integer values from 23 to
        32,767 are allowed for the 4/5 prescaler. For the 8/9 prescaler,
        the minimum integer value is 75, and the maximum value is
        65,535.
        </field>
        <field name="PRESCALER" bits="20">
        The dual modulus prescaler (P/P + 1), along with the INT,
        FRACx, and MODx counters, determines the overall division
        ratio from the VCO output to the PFD input. The PR1 bit
        (Bit DB20) in Register 0 sets the prescaler value.
        Operating at CML levels, the prescaler takes the clock from the
        VCO output and divides it down for the counters. It is based on
        a synchronous 4/5 core. When the prescaler is set to 4/5, the
        maximum RF frequency allowed is 7 GHz. The prescaler limits
        the INT value; therefore, if P is 4/5, NMIN is 23, and if P is 8/9,
        NMIN is 75.
        </field>
        <field name="AUTOCAL" bits="21">
        Write to Register 0 to enact (by default) the VCO automatic
        calibration, and to choose the appropriate VCO and VCO
        subband. Write 1 to the AC1 bit (Bit DB21) to enable the
        automatic calibration, which is the recommended mode of
        operation.
        Set the AC1 bit (Bit DB21) to 0 to disable the automatic
        calibration, which leaves the ADF5355 in the same band it was
        already in when Register 0 is updated.
        Disable the automatic calibration only for fixed frequency
        applications, phase adjust applications, or very small (&lt;10 kHz)
        frequency jumps.
        Toggling automatic calibration (AUTOCAL) is also required
        when changing frequency. See the Frequency Update Sequence
        section for more information.
        </field>
        <field name="RESERVED0" bits="31:22">
        Must be set to 0
        </field>
        <field name="CTL0" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0x0
        </field>
    </register>
    
    <register address="0x01" default_value="0x6C00001" name="REG1">
        <field name="RESERVED1" bits="31:28">
        Must be set to 0
        </field>
        <field name="FRAC1" bits="27:4">
        The 24 FRAC1 bits (Bits[DB27:DB4]) set the numerator of the
        fraction that is input to the Σ-Δ modulator. This fraction, along
        with the INT value, specifies the new frequency channel that
        the synthesizer locks to, as shown in the RF Synthesizer—A
        Worked Example section. FRAC1 values from 0 to (MOD1 − 1)
        cover channels over a frequency range equal to the PFD
        reference frequency.
        </field>
        <field name="CTL1" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0x1
        </field>
    </register>

    <register address="0x02" default_value="0x00000012" name="REG2">
        <field name="FRAC2" bits="31:18">
        The 16 INT bits (Bits[DB19:DB4]) set the INT value, which
        determines the integer part of the feedback division factor. The
        INT value is used in Equation 3 (see the INT, FRAC, MOD, and
        R Counter Relationship section). All integer values from 23 to
        32,767 are allowed for the 4/5 prescaler. For the 8/9 prescaler,
        the minimum integer value is 75, and the maximum value is
        65,535.
        </field>
        <field name="MOD2" bits="17:4">
        The 14-bit auxiliary modulus value (Bits[DB17:DB4]) sets the
        auxiliary fractional modulus. Use MOD2 to correct any residual
        error due to the main fractional modulus.
        </field>
        <field name="CTL2" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0x2
        </field>
    </register>

    <register address="0x03" default_value="0x00000003" name="REG3">
        <field name="RESERVED3" bits="31">
        Must be 0
        </field>
        <field name="SD_LOAD_RESET" bits="30">
        When writing to Register 0, the Σ-Δ modulator resets. For
        applications in which the phase is continually adjusted, this may
        not be desirable; therefore, in these cases, the Σ-Δ reset can be
        disabled by writing a 1 to the SD1 bit (Bit DB30).
        </field>
        <field name="PHASE_RESYNC_EN" bits="29">
        To use the phase resynchronization feature, the PR1 bit (Bit DB29)
        must be set to 1. If unused, the bit can be programmed to 0. The
        phase resync timer must also be used in Register 12 to ensure
        that the resynchronization feature is applied after PLL has settled to
        the final frequency. If the PLL has not settled to the final frequency,
        phase resync may not function correctly. Resynchronization is
        useful in phased array and beam forming applications. It ensures
        repeatability of output phase when programming the same
        frequency. In phase critical applications that use frequencies
        requiring the output divider (&lt;3400 MHz), it is necessary to
        feed the N divider with the divided VCO frequency as distinct
        from the fundamental VCO frequency.
        This is achieved by programming the D13 bit (Bit DB24) in
        Register 6 to 0, which ensures divided feedback to the N divider.
        Phase resynchronization operates only when FRAC2 = 0.
        For resync applications, enable the SD load reset in Register 3
        by setting DB30 to 0.
        </field>
        <field name="PHASE_ADJUST" bits="28">
        To adjust the relative output phase of the ADF5355 on each
        Register 0 update, set the PA1 bit (Bit DB28) to 1. This feature
        differs from the resynchronization feature in that it is useful
        when adjustments to phase are made continually in an
        application. For this function, disable the VCO automatic
        calibration by setting the AC1 bit (Bit DB21) in Register 0 to 0,
        and disable the SD load reset by setting the SD1 bit (Bit DB30)
        in Register 3 to 1. Note that phase resync and phase adjust
        cannot be used simultaneously.
        </field>
        <field name="PHASE" bits="27:4">
        The phase of the RF output frequency can adjust in 24-bit steps,
        from 0° (0) to 360° (224 − 1). For phase adjust applications, the
        phase is set by
        (Phase Value/16,777,216) × 360°
        When the phase value is programmed to Register 3, each
        subsequent adjustment of Register 0 increments the phase by
        the value in this equation.
        </field>
        
        <field name="CTL3" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0x3
        </field>
    </register>

    <register address="0x04" default_value="0x32008B84" name="REG4">
        <field name="RESERVED4" bits="31:30">
        Must be 0.
        </field>
        <field name="MUXOUT" bits="29:27">
        The on-chip multiplexer (MUXOUT) is controlled by
        Bits[DB29:DB27]. For additional details, see Figure 45.
        When changing frequency, that is, writing Register 0, MUXOUT
        must not be set to N divider output or R divider output. If needed,
        enable these functions after locking to the new frequency.
        0x00: three-state output
        0x01: DVDD
        0x02: DGND
        0x03: R divider output
        0x04: N divicer output
        0x05: analog lock detect
        0x06: digital lock detect
        0x07: reserved
        </field>
        <field name="REF_DBLR" bits="26">
        Setting the RD2 bit (Bit DB26) to 0 feeds the reference frequency
        signal directly to the 10-bit R counter, disabling the doubler.
        Setting this bit to 1 multiplies the reference frequency by a factor
        of 2 before feeding it into the 10-bit R counter. When the doubler
        is disabled, the REFIN falling edge is the active edge at the PFD
        input to the fractional synthesizer. When the doubler is enabled,
        both the rising and falling edges of the reference frequency become
        active edges at the PFD input.
        The maximum allowable reference frequency when the doubler
        is enabled is 100 MHz.
        </field>
        <field name="RDIV2" bits="25">
        Setting the RDIV2 bit (Bit DB25) to 1 inserts a divide by 2,
        toggle flip-flop between the R counter and PFD, which extends
        the maximum reference frequency input rate. This function
        provides a 50% duty cycle signal at the PFD input.
        </field>
        <field name="R" bits="24:15">
        The 10-bit R counter divides the input reference frequency
        (REFIN) to produce the reference clock to the PFD. Division
        ratios range from 1 to 1023.
        </field>
        <field name="DBL_BUF" bits="14">
        The D1 bit (Bit DB14) enables or disables double buffering of
        the RF divider select bits (Bits[DB23:DB21]) in Register 6. The
        Program Modes section explains how double buffering works.
        </field>
        <field name="CP_CURRENT" bits="13:10">
        The CP4 to CP1 bits (Bits[DB13:DB10]) set the charge pump
        current. Set this value to the charge pump current that the loop
        filter is designed with (see Figure 45). For the lowest spurs, the
        0.9 mA setting is recommended.
        </field>
        <field name="REF_MODE" bits="9">
        The ADF5355 permits use of either differential or single-ended
        reference sources.
        For optimum integer boundary spur performance, it is
        recommended to use the single-ended setting for all references
        up to 250 MHz (even if using a differential reference signal). Use
        the differential setting for reference frequencies above 250 MHz.
        </field>
        <field name="MUX_LOGIC" bits="8">
        To assist with logic compatibility, MUXOUT is programmable to
        two logic levels. Set the U5 bit (Bit DB8) to 0 to select 1.8 V
        logic, and set it to 1 to select 3.3 V logic.
        </field>
        <field name="PD_POLARITY" bits="7">
        The U4 bit (Bit DB7) sets the phase detector polarity. When a
        passive loop filter or a noninverting active loop filter is used, set
        DB7 to 1 (positive). If an active filter with an inverting
        characteristic is used, set this bit to 0 (negative).
        </field>
        <field name="PD" bits="6">
        The U3 bit (Bit DB6) sets the programmable power-down mode.
        Setting DB6 to 1 performs a power-down. Setting DB6 to 0 returns
        the synthesizer to normal operation. In software or hardware
        power-down mode, the ADF5355 retains all information in its
        registers. The register contents are only lost if the supply voltages
        are removed.
        When power-down activates, the following events occur:
        • The synthesizer counters are forced to their load state
        conditions.
        • The VCO powers down.
        • The charge pump is forced into three-state mode.
        • The digital lock detect circuitry resets.
        • The RFOUTA+/RFOUTA− and RFOUTB output stages are
        disabled.
        • The input registers remain active and capable of loading
        and latching data.
        </field>
        <field name="CP_3STATE" bits="5">
        Setting the U2 bit (Bit DB5) to 1 puts the charge pump into
        three-state mode. Set DB5 to 0 for normal operation.
        </field>
        <field name="COUNTER_RESET" bits="4">
        The U1 bit (Bit DB4) resets the R counter, N counter, and VCO
        band select of the ADF5355. When DB4 is set to 1, the RF
        synthesizer N counter, R counter, and VCO band select are reset.
        For normal operation, set DB4 to 0.
        Toggling counter reset is also required when changing frequency.
        See the Frequency Update Sequence section for more information.
        </field>
        
        <field name="CTL4" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0x4
        </field>
    </register>

    <register address="0x05" default_value="0x00800025" name="REG5">
        <field name="RESERVED5" bits="31:4">
        The bits in Register 5 are reserved and must be programmed as
        described in Figure 46, using a hexadecimal word of 0x00800025.
        </field>
        <field name="CTL5" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0x5
        </field>
    </register>

    <register address="0x06" default_value="0x35012036" name="REG6">
        <field name="RESERVED6" bits="31">
        Must be 0.
        </field>
        <field name="GATED_BLEED" bits="30">
        Bleed currents can be used for improving phase noise and spurs;
        however, due to a potential impact on lock time, the gated bleed
        bit, BL10 (Bit DB30), if set to 1, ensures bleed currents are not
        switched on until the digital lock detect asserts logic high. Note
        that this function requires digital lock detect to be enabled.
        </field>
        <field name="NEGATIVE_BLEED" bits="29">
        Use of constant negative bleed is recommended for most
        fractional-N applications because it improves the linearity of
        the charge pump, leading to lower noise and spurious signals than
        leaving it off. To enable negative bleed, write 1 to BL9 (Bit DB29),
        and to disable negative bleed, write 0 to BL9 (Bit DB29).
        Do not use negative bleed when operating in integer-N mode,
        that is, when FRAC1 = FRAC2 = 0, or when fPFD is greater than
        100 MHz.
        </field>
        <field name="RESERVED6_2" bits="28:25">
        Set to 0xA (0b1010)
        </field>
        <field name="FEEDBACK_SEL" bits="24">
        D13 (Bit DB24) selects the feedback from the output of the
        VCO to the N counter. When D13 is set to 1, the signal is taken
        directly from the VCO. When this bit is set to 0, the signal is
        taken from the output of the output dividers. The dividers
        enable coverage of the wide frequency band (3.4 GHz to 6.8 GHz).
        When the divider is enabled and the feedback signal is taken
        from the output, the RF output signals of two separately
        configured PLLs are in phase. Divided feedback is useful in
        some applications where the positive interference of signals is
        required to increase the power.
        </field>
        <field name="RF_DIVIDER_SEL" bits="23:21">
        D12 to D10 (Bits[DB23:DB21]) select the value of the RF output
        divider (see Figure 47).
        </field>
        <field name="CP_BLEED_CURRENT" bits="20:13">
        BL8 to BL1 (Bits[DB20:DB13]) control the level of the bleed
        current added to the charge pump output. This current
        optimizes the phase noise and spurious levels from the device.
        Tests have shown that the optimal bleed set is the following:
        4/N &lt; IBLEED/ICP &lt; 10/N
        where:
        N is the value of the feedback counter from the VCO to the PFD.
        IBLEED is the value of constant negative bleed applied to the
        charge pump, which is set by the contents of Bits[DB20:DB13].
        ICP is the value of charge pump current setting, Bits[DB13:DB10] of
        Register 4.
        </field>
        <field name="RESERVED6_B" bits="12">
        Must be 0.
        </field>
        <field name="MTLD" bits="11">
        When D8 (Bit DB11) is set to 1, the supply current to the RF
        output stage is shut down until the device achieves lock, as
        determined by the digital lock detect circuitry.
        </field>
        <field name="RF_OUT_B" bits="10">
        D7 (Bit DB10) enables or disables the high frequency RF output
        (RFOUTB). If DB10 is set to 0, the auxiliary high frequency RF
        output is enabled. If DB10 is set to 1, the auxiliary RF output is
        disabled.
        </field>
        <field name="RESERVED6_C" bits="9:7">
        Must be 0.
        </field>
        <field name="RF_OUT_A" bits="6">
        D3 (Bit DB6) enables or disables the primary RF output
        (RFOUTA+/RFOUTA−). If DB6 is set to 0, the primary RF output
        is disabled. If DB6 is set to 1, the primary RF output is enabled.
        </field>
        <field name="RF_OUT_PWR" bits="5:4">
        D2 and D1 (Bits[DB5:DB4]) set the value of the primary RF
        output power level (see Figure 47).
        </field>

        <field name="CTL6" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0x6
        </field>
    </register>

    <register address="0x07" default_value="0x040000E7" name="REG7">
        
        <field name="RESERVED7" bits="31:28">
        Must be set to 0
        </field>
        <field name="LE_SYNC_EDGE" bits="27">
        LE2 (bit DB27) allows selection of the synchronization load 
        enable (LE) edge to the falling or rising edge of the reference
        clock, which is useful for applications that require synchronization
        to a common reference edge. To use this bit, LE 
        synchronization (bit DB25) must be set to 1.
        </field>
        <field name="RESERVED7_B" bits="26">
        Must be set to 0
        </field>
        <field name="LE_SYNC" bits="25">
        When set to 1, Bit DB25 ensures that the load enable (LE) edge
        is synchronized internally with the rising edge of reference
        input frequency. This synchronization prevents the rare event of
        reference and RF dividers loading at the same time as a falling edge
        of the reference frequency, which can lead to longer lock times.
        </field>
        <field name="RESERVED7_A" bits="24:10">
        Must be 0.
        </field>
        <field name="LD_CYCL_CNT" bits="9:8">
        LD5 and LD4 (Bits[DB9:DB8]) set the number of consecutive
        cycles counted by the lock detect circuitry before asserting lock
        detect high. See Figure 48 for details.
        </field>
        <field name="LOL_MODE" bits="7">
        Set the LOL mode bit (Bit DB7) to 1 when the application is a
        fixed frequency application in which the reference (REFIN) is
        likely to be removed, such as a clocking application. The standard
        lock detect circuit assumes that REFIN is always present; however,
        this may not be the case with clocking applications. To enable this
        functionality, set DB7 to 1. LOL mode does not function reliably
        when using differential REFIN mode.
        </field>
        <field name="FRACN_LD_PRECISION" bits="6:5">
        LD3 and LD2 (Bits[DB6:DB5]) set the precision of the lock detect
        circuitry in fractional-N mode. LDP is available at 5 ns, 6 ns, 8 ns,
        or 12 ns. If bleed currents are used, use 12 ns.
        </field>
        <field name="LD_MODE" bits="4">
        If LD1 (Bit DB4) is set to 0, each reference cycle is set by
        fractional-N lock detect precision as described in the
        Fractional-N Lock Detect Count (LDC) section. If DB4 is
        set to 1, each reference cycle is 2.9 ns long, which is more
        appropriate for integer-N applications.
        </field>
        
        <field name="CTL7" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0x7
        </field>
    </register>

    <register address="0x08" default_value="0x102D0428" name="REG8">
        <field name="RESERVED8" bits="31:4">
        The bits in this register are reserved and must be programmed as
        shown in Figure 49, using a hexadecimal word of 0x102D0428.
        </field>
        <field name="CTL8" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0x8
        </field>
    </register>
    
    <register address="0x09" default_value="0x1A19FCC9" name="REG9">
        <field name="VCO_BAND_DIVISION" bits="31:24">
        VC8 to VC1 (Bits[DB31:DB24]) set the value of the VCO band
        division clock. Determine the value of this clock by
        VCO Band Div = Ceiling(fPFD/2,400,000)
        </field>
        <field name="TIMEOUT" bits="23:14">
        TL10 to TL1 (Bits[DB23:DB14]) set the timeout value for the
        VCO band select.
        </field>
        <field name="AUTO_LVL_TIMEOUT" bits="13:9">
        AL5 to AL1 (Bits[DB13:DB9]) set the timer value used for the
        automatic level calibration of the VCO. This function combines
        the PFD frequency, the timeout variable, and ALC wait variable.
        Choose the ALC such that the following equation is always
        greater than 50 μs.
        ALC Wait &gt; (50 μs × fPFD)/Timeout
        </field>
        <field name="SYNTH_LOCK_TIMEOUT" bits="8:4">
        SL5 to SL1 (Bits[DB8:DB4]) set the synthesizer lock timeout
        value. This value allows the VTUNE force to settle on the VTUNE
        pin. The value must be 20 μs. Calculate the value using the
        following equation:
        Synthesizer Lock Timeout &gt; (20 μs × fPFD)/Timeout
        </field>
        <field name="CTL9" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0x9
        </field>
    </register>
    
    <register address="0x0A" default_value="0x00C026BA" name="REG10">
        <field name="RESERVED10" bits="31:14">
        Must be set to 0x300.
        Bits[DB31:DB14] are reserved. Bits[DB23:DB22] must be set to
        11, and all other bits in this range must be set to 0.
        </field>
        <field name="ADC_CLK_DIV" bits="13:6">
        An on-board analog-to-digital converter (ADC) determines the
        VTUNE setpoint relative to the ambient temperature of the
        ADF5355 environment. The ADC ensures that the initial tuning
        voltage in any application is chosen correctly to avoid any
        temperature drift issues.
        The ADC uses a clock that is equal to the output of the R
        counter (or the PFD frequency) divided by ADC_CLK_DIV.
        AD8 to AD1 (Bits[DB13:DB6]) set the value of this divider. On
        power-up, the R counter is not programmed; however, in these
        power-up cases, it defaults to R = 1.
        Choose the value such that
        ADC_CLK_DIV = Ceiling(((fPFD/100,000) − 2)/4)
        where Ceiling() rounds up to the nearest integer.
        For example, for fPFD = 61.44 MHz, set ALC_CLK_DIV = 154
        so that the ADC clock frequency is 99.417 kHz.
        If ADC_CLK_DIV is greater than 255, set it to 255.
        </field>
        <field name="ADC_CONV" bits="5">
        AE2 (Bit DB5) ensures that the ADC performs a conversion
        when a write to Register 10 is performed. It is recommended to
        enable this mode.
        </field>
        <field name="ADC_EN" bits="4">
        AE1 (Bit DB4), when set to 1, powers up the ADC for the
        temperature dependent VTUNE calibration. It is recommended to
        always use this function.
        </field>
        <field name="CTL10" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0xA
        </field>
    </register>

    <register address="0x0B" default_value="0x0061300B" name="REG11">
        <field name="RESERVED11_A" bits="31:25">
        Must be set to 0.
        </field>
        <field name="VCO_BAND_HOLD" bits="24">
        When set to 1, prevents a reset of the VCO core, band, and
        bias during a counter reset. VCO band hold is required for 
        applicatkons that use external PLLs.
        </field>
        <field name="RESERVED11" bits="23:4">
        Must be set to 0x61300.
        </field>
        <field name="CTL11" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0xB
        </field>
    </register>
    
    <register address="0x0C" default_value="0xFFFFF5FC" name="REG12">
        <field name="PHASE_RESYNC" bits="31:12">
        P20 to P1 (Bits[DB31:DB12]) set the timeout counter for
        activation of phase resync. This value must be set such that
        a resync happens immediately after (and not before) the PLL
        has achieved lock after reprogramming.
        Calculate the timeout value using the following equation:
        Time Out Value = Phase Resync Clock Divider/fPFD
        When not using phase resynchronization set these bits to 
        1 for normal operation
        </field>
        <field name="RESERVED12" bits="11:4">
        These bits are reserved. Bit DB11 and DB9 must be 
        set to 0. All other bits in this range must be set to 1.
        </field>
        
        <field name="CTL12" bits="3:0">
        control bits. 0xC
        </field>
    </register>

    <register address="0x0D" default_value="0x0000000D" name="REG13">
      <field name="FRAC2_MSB" bits="31:18">
      THis value is used with the auxiliary fractional LSB value
      (Register 2, bits[DB31:DB18]) to generate the total auxiliary
      fractional FRAC2 value.
        FRAC2 = (FRAC2_MSB * 2**14) + FRAC2_LSB
      These bits can be set to all zeros to ensure software
      compatibility with the ADF5355
      </field>
      <field name="MOD2_MSB" bits="17:4">
        This value is used with the auxiliary fractional MSB value
        (Register 2, bit{DB17:DB4]) to generate the total auxiliary
        modulus MOD2 value
          MOD2 = (MOD2_MSB * 2**14) + MOD2_LSB
      </field>
        
      <field name="CTL13" bits="3:0">
      control bits. 0xD
      </field>
    </register>
</register_map>
